kicking-carbs.com 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy - Kicking Carbs

This privacy and disclosure policy sets out how Kicking Carbs uses and protects any information that you give while using https://Kicking-Carbs.com.

**CONTACT INFO:**  
email- wendy(at)wendypolisi(dot)com

**PRIVACY POLICY**  
Should we ask you to provide specific information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used under this privacy statement.

Kicking Carbs may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from August 1, 2016. Updated Feb 21, 2019.

Kicking Carbs believes very firmly in keeping your personal information confidential. The following policy describes what information we collect and how it is used and shared.

**INFORMATION COLLECTED**  
Kicking Carbs collects as little information as possible from users who post comments and messages. We will typically collect a name (either real or alias), personal website, and e-mail address. While the name and email are required as proof of you being a real person the website is not a requirement and you can leave it blank.

**Cookies / IP Address tracking**  
Kicking Carbs uses cookies to uniquely identify users for the purpose of log files, posting comments, rating recipes, and possible giveaways on this site. No personal information is stored in these cookies and it simply a way to identify your computer.

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. Find out more in our specific cookie policy.

**With Whom Information is Shared**

None of your information will be shared with third parties. Kicking Carbs may use your e-mail address in the future to contact you regarding the site, newsletter, or with important information, however, an opt-out will always be provided. Your name and website may be displayed on the site if you post a comment or a message in the forum. However, your e-mail address and privacy will always be kept secure.

**Opting Out**

If Kicking Carbs chooses to send out newsletter updates in the future and we have your email address on file, you may receive a copy of our newsletter. However, at the bottom of every newsletter will be an easy way to opt-out. The editors of our site hate SPAM as much as you and have no intention of filling up e-mail boxes with unwanted messages.

**THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING**  
We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit Network Advertising (NAI).

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is Mediavine. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

**SECURITY**  
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**CONTROLLING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes  
If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.  
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us at the email address above.

**DISCLOSURE:**  
Kicking Carbs uses affiliate links like Amazon as a source of income. When you click on the links and then buy products the blog gets a percentage of the sale from the seller. This does not have an effect on your cost. Some posts are sponsored by advertisers/companies. These posts will always include full disclosure and be clearly labeled as sponsored. Some items that are reviewed are given to me by the company. This will always be noted. Restless Chipotle is a full disclosure blog – nothing hidden, ever. I promise.

This policy is valid from 18 July 2015 and last updated May 14, 2018

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me. For questions about this blog, please contact wendy at Kicking-Carbs.com

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. We believe in honesty of relationship, opinion and identity. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content.

Kicking Carbs is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though I and other bloggers may receive compensation for posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinion, findings, beliefs, and/or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.
